{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The output of an AND gate with three inputs, A, B, and C, is HIGH when ________.", "opta": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 0", "optb": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0", "optc": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1", "optd": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 3-input NOR gate has eight input possibilities, how many of those possibilities will result in a HIGH output?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a signal passing through a gate is inhibited by sending a LOW into one of the inputs, and the output is HIGH, the gate is a(n):", "opta": "AND", "optb": "NAND", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "OR", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A device used to display one or more digital signals so that they can be compared to expected timing diagrams for the signals is a:", "opta": "DMM", "optb": "spectrum analyzer", "optc": "logic analyzer", "optd": "frequency counter", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When used with an IC, what does the term \"QUAD\" indicate?", "opta": "2 circuits", "optb": "4 circuits", "optc": "6 circuits", "optd": "8 circuits", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an OR gate with three inputs, A, B, and C, is LOW when ________.", "opta": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0", "optb": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1", "optc": "A = 0, B = 1, C = 1", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following logical operations is represented by the + sign in Boolean algebra?", "opta": "inversion", "optb": "AND", "optc": "OR", "optd": "complementation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Output will be a LOW for any case when one or more inputs are zero for a(n):", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "NOT gate", "optc": "AND gate", "optd": "NOR gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many pins does the 4049 IC have?", "opta": "14", "optb": "16", "optc": "18", "optd": "20", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following choices meets the minimum requirement needed to create specialized waveforms that are used in digital control and sequencing circuits?", "opta": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, and a repetitive waveform generator", "optb": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, and a Johnson shift counter", "optc": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, and a DeMorgan pulse generator", "optd": "basic gates, a clock oscillator, a repetitive waveform generator, and a Johnson shift counter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "TTL operates from a ________.", "opta": "9-volt supply", "optb": "3-volt supply", "optc": "12-volt supply", "optd": "5-volt supply", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NOR gate is HIGH if ________.", "opta": "all inputs are HIGH", "optb": "any input is HIGH", "optc": "any input is LOW", "optd": "all inputs are LOW", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The switching speed of CMOS is now ________.", "opta": "competitive with TTL", "optb": "three times that of TTL", "optc": "slower than TTL", "optd": "twice that of TTL", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The format used to present the logic output for the various combinations of logic inputs to a gate is called a(n):", "opta": "Boolean constant", "optb": "Boolean variable", "optc": "truth table", "optd": "input logic function", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The power dissipation, PD, of a logic gate is the product of the ________.", "opta": "dc supply voltage and the peak current", "optb": "dc supply voltage and the average supply current", "optc": "ac supply voltage and the peak current", "optd": "ac supply voltage and the average supply current", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is again applied to the pins of a 7421 IC with the following results. Is there a problem with the circuit and if so, what is the problem?", "opta": "Pin 6 should be ON.", "optb": "Pin 8 should be ON.", "optc": "Pin 8 should be pulsing.", "optd": "no problem", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 3-input AND gate has eight input possibilities, how many of those possibilities will result in a HIGH output?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression for a 3-input AND gate is ________.", "opta": "X = AB", "optb": "X = ABC", "optc": "X = A + B + C", "optd": "X = AB + C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A CMOS IC operating from a 3-volt supply will consume ________.", "opta": "less power than a TTL IC", "optb": "more power than a TTL IC", "optc": "the same power as a TTL IC", "optd": "no power at all", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the small bubble on the output of the NAND gate logic symbol mean?", "opta": "open collector output", "optb": "tristate", "optc": "The output is inverted.", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the pin numbers of the outputs of the gates in a 7432 IC?", "opta": "3, 6, 10, and 13", "optb": "1, 4, 10, and 13", "optc": "3, 6, 8, and 11", "optd": "1, 4, 8, and 11", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NOT gate is HIGH when ________.", "opta": "the input is LOW", "optb": "the input is HIGH", "optc": "power is applied to the gate's IC", "optd": "power is removed from the gate's IC", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the input to a NOT gate is A and the output is X, then ________.", "opta": "X = A", "optb": "", "optc": "X = 0", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is used to test the pins of a 7411 IC with the following results. Is there a problem with the chip and if so, what is the problem?", "opta": "Pin 6 should be ON.", "optb": "Pin 6 should be pulsing.", "optc": "Pin 8 should be ON.", "optd": "no problem", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs of a four-input AND gate must be HIGH in order for the output of the logic gate to go HIGH?", "opta": "any one of the inputs", "optb": "any two of the inputs", "optc": "any three of the inputs", "optd": "all four inputs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the output of a three-input AND gate must be a logic LOW, what must the condition of the inputs be?", "opta": "All inputs must be LOW.", "optb": "All inputs must be HIGH.", "optc": "At least one input must be LOW.", "optd": "At least one input must be HIGH.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Logically, the output of a NOR gate would have the same Boolean expression as a(n):", "opta": "NAND gate immediately followed by an inverter", "optb": "OR gate immediately followed by an inverter", "optc": "AND gate immediately followed by an inverter", "optd": "NOR gate immediately followed by an inverter", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A logic probe is placed on the output of a gate and the display indicator is dim. A pulser is used on each of the input terminals, but the output indication does not change. What is wrong?", "opta": "The dim indication on the logic probe indicates that the supply voltage is probably low.", "optb": "The output of the gate appears to be open.", "optc": "The dim indication is the result of a bad ground connection on the logic probe.", "optd": "The gate is a tristate device.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the Boolean expression for a three-input AND gate?", "opta": "X = A + B + C", "optb": "X = A  \u00b7 B \u00b7 C", "optc": "A \u2013 B \u2013 C", "optd": "A $ B $ C", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gates has the exact inverse output of the OR gate for all possible input combinations?", "opta": "NOR", "optb": "NOT", "optc": "NAND", "optd": "AND", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between a 7400 and a 7411 IC?", "opta": "7400 has two four-input NAND gates; 7411 has three three-input AND gates", "optb": "7400 has four two-input NAND gates; 7411 has three three-input AND gates", "optc": "7400 has two four-input AND gates; 7411 has three three-input NAND gates", "optd": "7400 has four two-input AND gates; 7411 has three three-input NAND gates", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Write the Boolean expression for an inverter logic gate with input C and output Y.", "opta": "Y = C", "optb": "Y =", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an exclusive-OR gate is HIGH if ________.", "opta": "all inputs are LOW", "optb": "all inputs are HIGH", "optc": "the inputs are unequal", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A clock signal with a period of 1 s is applied to the input of an enable gate. The output must contain six pulses. How long must the enable pulse be active?", "opta": "Enable must be active for 0 s.", "optb": "Enable must be active for 3 s.", "optc": "Enable must be active for 6 s.", "optd": "Enable must be active for 12 s.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The AND function can be used to ________ and the OR function can be used to ________ .", "opta": "enable, disable", "optb": "disable, enable", "optc": "enable or disable, enable or disable", "optd": "detect, invert", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One advantage TTL has over CMOS is that TTL is ________.", "opta": "less expensive", "optb": "not sensitive to electrostatic discharge", "optc": "faster", "optd": "more widely available", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 2-input NOR gate is equivalent to a ________.", "opta": "negative-OR gate", "optb": "negative-AND gate", "optc": "negative-NAND gate", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 3-input OR gate has eight input possibilities, how many of those possibilities will result in a HIGH output?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fan-out is specified in terms of ________.", "opta": "voltage", "optb": "current", "optc": "wattage", "optd": "unit loads", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many input combinations would a truth table have for a six-input AND gate?", "opta": "32", "optb": "48", "optc": "64", "optd": "128", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the circuit number of the IC that contains four two-input AND gates in standard TTL?", "opta": "7402", "optb": "7404", "optc": "7408", "optd": "7432", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The terms \"low speed\" and \"high speed,\" applied to logic circuits, refer to the ________.", "opta": "rise time", "optb": "fall time", "optc": "propagation delay time", "optd": "clock speed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The NOR logic gate is the same as the operation of the ________ gate with an inverter connected to the output.", "opta": "OR", "optb": "AND", "optc": "NAND", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic expression for a NOR gate is ________.", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With regard to an AND gate, which statement is true?", "opta": "An AND gate has two inputs and one output.", "optb": "An AND gate has two or more inputs and two outputs.", "optc": "If one input to a 2-input AND gate is HIGH, the output reflects the other input.", "optd": "A 2-input AND gate has eight input possibilities.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term \"hex inverter\" refers to:", "opta": "an inverter that has six inputs", "optb": "six inverters in a single package", "optc": "a six-input symbolic logic device", "optd": "an inverter that has a history of failure", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many inputs are on the logic gates of a 74HC21 IC?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic logic gate whose output is the complement of the input is the:", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "inverter", "optd": "comparator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When reading a Boolean expression, what does the word \"NOT\" indicate?", "opta": "the same as", "optb": "inversion", "optc": "high", "optd": "low", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of an exclusive-NOR gate is HIGH if ________.", "opta": "the inputs are equal", "optb": "one input is HIGH, and the other input is LOW", "optc": "the inputs are unequal", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many AND gates are found in a 7411 IC?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following equations would accurately describe a four-input OR gate when A = 1, B = 1, C = 0, and D = 0?", "opta": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 01", "optb": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 1", "optc": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 0", "optd": "1 + 1 + 0 + 0 = 00", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of a digital circuit that produces several repetitive digital waveforms?", "opta": "an inverter", "optb": "an OR gate", "optc": "a Johnson shift counter", "optd": "an AND gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic types of programmable arrays are made up of ________.", "opta": "AND gates", "optb": "OR gates", "optc": "NAND and NOR gates", "optd": "AND gates and OR gates", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic gate that will have HIGH or \"1\" at its output when any one (or more) of its inputs is HIGH is a(n):", "opta": "OR gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "NOR gate", "optd": "NOT operation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "CMOS IC packages are available in ________.", "opta": "DIP configuration", "optb": "SOIC configuration", "optc": "DIP and SOIC configurations", "optd": "neither DIP nor SOIC configurations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a basic Boolean operation?", "opta": "OR", "optb": "NOT", "optc": "AND", "optd": "FOR", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gates is described by the expression ?", "opta": "OR", "optb": "AND", "optc": "NOR", "optd": "NAND", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the Boolean expression for a four-input OR gate?", "opta": "Y = A + B + C + D", "optb": "Y = A\u00b7 B \u00b7 C \u00b7 D", "optc": "Y = A \u2013 B \u2013 C \u2013 D", "optd": "Y = A $ B $ C $ D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many truth table entries are necessary for a four-input circuit?", "opta": "4", "optb": "8", "optc": "12", "optd": "16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many entries would a truth table for a four-input NAND gate have?", "opta": "2", "optb": "8", "optc": "16", "optd": "32", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Boolean expression for a 3-input OR gate is ________.", "opta": "X = A + B", "optb": "X = A + B + C", "optc": "X = ABC", "optd": "X = A + BC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From the truth table for a three-input NOR gate, what is the only condition of inputs A, B, and C that will make the output X high?", "opta": "A = 1, B = 1, C = 1", "optb": "A = 1, B = 0, C = 0", "optc": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 1", "optd": "A = 0, B = 0, C = 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The logic gate that will have a LOW output when any one of its inputs is HIGH is the:", "opta": "NAND gate", "optb": "AND gate", "optc": "NOR gate", "optd": "OR gate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The output of a NAND gate is LOW if ________.", "opta": "all inputs are LOW", "optb": "all inputs are HIGH", "optc": "any input is LOW", "optd": "any input is HIGH", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}